# CHASE ROBERTSON

Auckland, NZ  $\diamond$  Mobile: +64 022 695 5126

chaserobertson 208@gmail.com ♦ github.com/chaserobertson ♦ linkedin.com/in/chase-robertson

## CAREER OBJECTIVE

I want to turn raw data into real insights. I love designing, implementing, and effectively communicating the results of data systems.

I am passionate about extracting the real human interests hidden within raw empirical information by applying the right technical tools. Whether it be high-level collaboration and design, mid-level program structure and tool selection, or low-level pre-processing and optimisation, it is solidly in my wheelhouse. Solving the inevitable technical puzzles along the way is all part of the fun!

## SKILLS SUMMARY

## **Problem Solving**

I needed to revive more than 70 frozen teleconferencing control devices after a breaking update from Zoom, and didn't have the time to factory reset and restore them all individually. Instead, I found a web interaction automation tool and programmed the reset steps, then retrieved the 70 device IP addresses and fed them into the script to execute the change all at once. Mission accomplished, and when the next breaking update arrived, we were ready with the same scripted fix. Technical challenges like this one excite me, and I know I have the capacity to find or create the tools necessary to solve them.

## **Data Analysis**

A device was stolen from the company's multi-million-dollar device inventory - or was it more than one device? To answer this simple but crucial question, I needed information from six different sources, and I needed it all in one place. By joining each data set by device identifier, filtering down to the important details, and grouping by number of verification tests passed, a single number was reached which could be used as an estimate of the scale of theft. Not only was this work applauded by senior-level software engineering directors, it also led to real security improvement, and turned out to be a fun technical challenge.

#### Critical Evaluation

I have often had the opportunity to practice critical evaluation of others' work, especially in my job as a tutor for the Computer Science department at the University of Auckland. I have been called upon consistently to provide a critical eye toward lecturers' work, and find my attention to detail especially helpful in executing this. Whether it be in reviewing example code or proofreading exam questions, I am trusted to spend the time and attention necessary to fish out hidden issues.

## Systems Design

The company was hiring hundreds of new employees, and there were not enough IT staff to execute the purchasing, setup, and training tasks necessary to facilitate those hires. I had the opportunity to design a

more efficient system from the ground up to better meet this need. Information sharing was automated by integrating our tracking data with HR data using Google Apps Scripts and other automation tools, so we could always stay organised. Manual steps were whittled down to just the essentials with device provisioning scripts and manual process optimisation. And all of these changes were executed in a modular fashion, such that the performance of each new process could be compared and approved right away.

#### EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Graduate Teaching Assistant at The University of Auckland	02/2022 - Present
Systems Administrator at Lucid Software	02/2021 - 07/2021
IT Specialist II at Lucid Software	02/2020 - 02/2021
IT Helpdesk Technician at Lucid Software	09/2018 - 02/2019

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Data Science	Expected Graduation $11/2023$
University of Auckland	$Auckland,\ NZ$

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
Brigham Young University

01/2014 - 05/2018 Utah, USA

## **DETAILED EXPERIENCE**

## Graduate Teaching Assistant at The University of Auckland

02/2022 - Present

Graduate Teaching Assistant for COMPSCI 101 during Semester 1 2022. Lead tutorial sessions, assist students with lab work, and proofread course and exam materials.

## Systems Administrator at Lucid Software

02/2021 - 07/2021

Mainly focused on migration of Jira Software on-prem to Cloud. Also worked on internal identity system integrations, fleet management, and mentoring of fellow team members.

## IT Specialist II at Lucid Software

02/2020 - 02/2021

Administered physical technology stack for company of about 800 employees, including Mac/Windows/Linux workstations, conference room A/V devices, and office network.

## IT Helpdesk Technician at Lucid Software

09/2018 - 02/2019

Managed daily IT operations including new employee on-boarding, event support, documentation, process improvement, and general troubleshooting.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python, R, SQL, Bash, PowerShell, C++, Java, Julia, C#, JavaScript

Tools git, sklearn, tidyverse, ggplot2, Selenium, TCP/IP, DNS, AWS, OpenVPN, Wireshark

Skills Data Engineering & Analysis, Critical Evaluation, Technical Writing, Troubleshooting

#### **PROJECTS**

## Polycom Phone Mgmt Python + Selenium

GitHub

- Scripted solutions to managing conference room controllers.
- Can retrieve status information from all phones to confirm availability.
- Can send out the reboot command to initiate automatic firmware updates or otherwise reset.
- Can restore new or frozen devices from a configuration file.

## **Dealer Scrape** Python + requests

GitHub

- Created a web scraper to retrieve reviews for a car dealership.
- Reviews were scored for over-positivity and ranked accordingly.

Other Projects GitHub

- advent Daily coding challenges through the month of December that are shockingly fun.
- macos-setup Personal laptop setup script to configure OS settings and install apps.
- globe An experiment with Observable and creative data visualisation.

## **INTERESTS**

My current hobbies include ice hockey, running, cooking soups, and long walks in the Auckland Domain. In past lives I have also experimented with van-life, rugby, ultimate frisbee, pole vaulting, backpacking, fly fishing, yoga, drumming, singing, building, motorcycling and related mechanics, and long bouts of travel. I have lived in the US, China, and a few different places in Central/South America, and have too many stamps in my passport. Academic interests include poverty and development economics, evolutionary psychology, and world history. Variety is the spice of life!

#### REFERENCES

#### Alan Reeves-Fortney

Senior Information Technology Manager at Lucid Software

arf@lucidchart.com

Alan was my manager at Lucid Software from 2019 to 2021.

#### Ann Cameron

Professional Teaching Fellow at UoA Faculty of Science

+6499234947

#### a.cameron@auckland.ac.nz

Ann is the course coordinator for COMPSCI 101 and can attest to my work as a tutor.